hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is
jeremiah krakowski and if you haven't
heard this podcast before i help coaches
trainers and consultants grow their
business past the 30 000 mark and beyond
we've had a number of clients that have
grown their businesses to over eight
figures it's over 10 million dollars
starting from scratch with the
techniques tools tips tricks and
strategies that we teach you on this
podcast now today i want to show you how
to learn any topic
faster than you've ever learned before
almost like a super human type
learning ability the truth is we live in
a world where artificial intelligence is
within our grasp
and
right now you have access to this type
of ai to help you learn different things
and so i'm going to give you some of my
strategies that you might not even
realize that you've been using to use ai
to learn faster okay
one of the biggest ways
is
youtube okay a lot of people don't
realize this
youtube has an algorithm that is
based off of artificial intelligence
that looks at what videos you watch what
videos you like
and then suggests
other pieces of content
to you based off of what you're watching
and so if you're trying to learn any
topic
youtube is one of the best places to
start and it will suggest
additional pieces of material for you
beyond that okay based off of what you
watch so like if you want to learn
principles about scaling your business
about
motivation about
thinking better about
programming about
marketing
youtube is one of the best places to go
and what it is is the algorithm is going
to show you
pieces of content so let's say you're
wondering about nfts right a lot of
people ask about nfts
so you type in nfts
and instantly you have the top videos
on the first page of youtube search
about the topic you could become
essentially
an expert
by watching through some of these videos
in less than
in less than an hour or two for free
and we have access to this at our
fingertips okay maybe you want to know
about about sales okay
uh or or or
selling more online
okay
you have access to
videos that are on youtube about
different topics now you might be like
okay
maybe i want to know about selling more
uh
coaching programs okay see then you want
to niche down you want to get specific
with
exactly what you're looking for and
learn how to search better so we have
access to youtube we also have access to
google again google uses artificial
intelligence to give you their search
results in fact they have a button here
that says how search works
our mission is to organize the world's
information to make it universally
accessible and useful okay
and so they go based off of what you're
searching they map the content
out they present it in a way that helps
you find the content now sure there's an
argument like oh this is uh
you know they're censoring stuff there's
censored content
on most of the topics you're gonna
search
unless it's like medically related
it's not really something you have to
worry about too much if you're looking
for stuff that is censored duckduckgo is
a search engine that you can go to
that is that is not
um
censored the way that that google is
okay why use it instead of they don't
have the trackers they're they're
stuff like that but
the problem with that is duckduckgo is
then based off of seo so honestly
if that's your reason for not using
google for not using youtube
realize that you're missing out on so
much information that you can learn i
hear from a lot of people like i don't
want to use amazon i don't want to use
youtube i don't want to use google i
don't want to use facebook or twitter
because it's owned by the the elites and
it's this conspiracy theory mindset that
we should no longer do business with
these companies whatever
i'm i'm i'm sorry but there's so much
access to information out there that
that it would be absolutely stupid to
operate and think that way uh to not use
those companies okay so for instance
google you can search any topic again
how to sell more online courses
and we have of course there's ads that
are the top right but we have
articles
i mean this is great kajabi they sell
so many courses this will teach you
any topic that that even i share with
you you can find the baseline level of
those topics
um
how to reach
restaurant owners
to sell services to them okay
how to approach restaurants to sell your
product
what's the best way to market services
for restaurant owners
how to sell
thyroid
support
online
okay so now this is more based off of
supplements how to sell
health
health care online
might be a better search
tips to sell health insurance how to
sell health products
and so these are just articles that are
all listed right here again you go to
youtube and what i'll usually do is i'll
search for
uh a topic on youtube i'll search for it
on google and and the truth is whether
you're selling insurance or health care
you can actually learn a lot from a lot
of these different videos because the
same mentality it's the same mentality
that people have
okay so we typed in right here how to
sell health care online it pulled up
more about health insurance then we
searched it in youtube and it pulled up
about selling insurance but these are
these are actually going to be videos
from people that they've put online
about how to sell in certain markets
such as healthcare health insurance and
so you want to find that information
just
by listening and learning you can grow
better at this now let's say that you're
not wanting to learn a topic that's
related to sales or your business okay
let's say you just want to learn
something in general so i've been
wanting to learn a lot about uh comic
books and writing so i looked up all the
videos that i could about about writing
novels
uh you know
how
how to how to write a novel okay
went through
different videos how to write
comic books
okay
went through these different videos this
channel was one that i really liked a
lot you can see a lot of them i've
watched through
these different videos
how to program
with with python okay this is about
programming you can learn all of this
over at youtube there's so much access
now the next level that i love is to go
over to amazon once i dive into some
videos
through youtube i go over to amazon and
i find all the books on the topic and
here's why i like books
books take
all of the overview of what would be in
videos and put them into one place that
you can go through and you take notes as
to what stands out to you okay
so
how to write comic books
stan lee's how to write comic books i
actually have the book right over there
art of comic book writing i have that
book over there
how to make comics like the pros i have
that book over there literally so i read
through these books
and they gave me a bird's-eye view of
the whole industry it actually showed me
that maybe i want to write a graphic not
a graphic novel but write a
young adult's novel so now i'm looking
at okay how to write
young adult fiction completely different
topic how to market a book writing young
adult fiction and so these are some of
the books that now i'm starting to
explore and starting to look at to learn
what i don't know about and this all
happens by it started with a google
search it started with youtube videos
and that's how i learned things that's
how you can learn stuff
faster
than most people
see i see a lot of people make the
excuse well
nobody ever showed me how to do that so
i can't do it
that's a that's a
it's a really lame excuse
because if you're living today
in in 2022
if you're living today in 2022
that that excuse that
nobody showed me
how to learn something
how to do it
is not valid
it's just not that was valid
15 20 years ago
and i don't mean to invalidate your
experience
um
but when it comes to the internet when
it comes to
what's available to us we could take
this to the next level and this is
something that i really want to show
with you you might say well i need
personal guidance and mentorship from
people
i have an answer for you
facebook groups
literally facebook groups
my facebook group
we we run facebook groups for people
we're there's a facebook group if you
want to learn how to how to trade stocks
that that that my mom runs
how to trade stocks in crypto how to
trade stocks in down markets like
there's a group if you want to learn
about
worship
songwriting
that you can join this is another client
of mine i have my group right here the
grow your life
community
where if you have any topic about your
business as a course creator coach or
trainer you can learn by posting in this
group as well as going through my
podcast
okay maybe those aren't the groups
you're looking for so what i did when i
was learning comic books i typed in
the word comic books and i found this
group right here
i create comic books 15 000 members
and i just started posting my questions
that i would ask a mentor
literally
i actually want to show you some of my
questions that i posted here
your content
here's some of the stuff i posted in the
group
here's some of the posts artists and
illustrators what would you look for in
a writer producer
i spent four years learning the process
one thing i'm not too picky controlling
other design
okay so i'm going to view this in the
group
the amount of responses that i got back
from people 23 comments
all from people i made friends with like
two of the people because i really liked
what they said asked them more questions
in direct message they were open to it
people are willing to help you if you're
willing to ask
people are willing to show you what you
don't know if you're willing to ask okay
so i posted it in this group
illustrators feedback desired writing a
script
i shared the example of the script
i shared
what the layout looked like
what the script looked like got 54
comments back from people
some of them were a little more critical
than i liked i learned to to develop
thicker skin around that
wasn't too worried
focus on the people that were more
supportive okay you're not going to be
supported by everybody but you will find
don't get into arguments with people
there's a lot of people that are out
there that are willing to support you
okay so then i posted okay
you know super thankful for this
community i'm a writer that can't draw
very visual imagination working my first
script when i hire what should i look
for 25 comments
from illustrators
right here
this is all just in the course of like
a couple weeks look at you can see the
time stamps march 31st april 18th april
19th april 20th
has anyone thought of merging
interactive
uh storytelling with comic
books and i said hey after being here
about a week i decided
not to make a whole comic book but maybe
an illustrated
book like this
got a ton of support from the community
that had followed my previous posts
these were all the same people that were
commenting back they're like this is so
cool i love it great idea you go for
like they were excited and cheering me
on
and and and and just a month prior like
i had no no clue on that i've been
studying it for about four years but
really had gained
very little knowledge on it until i
started reading the books watching the
videos on youtube and going through
facebook groups and asking questions
some of you are too afraid of other
people not responding the way you want
them to that you won't go out there and
post in facebook groups and ask for help
you've got to break past past that ego
that is stopping you from getting the
help you need because you're afraid of
how other people will respond
as well
you need to learn how to communicate
directly and specifically what you want
to learn from people if you're getting
vague answers is because you asked the
wrong questions that's it
so learning how to ask the right
questions how do we learn how to ask the
right questions we learn by asking more
questions see then this is the part
where most people will never get it
they'll watch this video
they'll never do anything with it
you're gonna ask the wrong questions
you're gonna make mistakes
you're gonna get some people that are
pissed off that you even asked
but you'll get better at asking
questions by doing it more
and so don't let the negative feedback
of five percent of people stop you from
doing the thing that's going to unlock
genius in your brain
there is no reason
no excuse
in 2022 to say nobody ever showed me how
to do something
nobody ever taught me
nobody ever walked me through the
process and so that's why i can't reach
my goals
it's the biggest load of crap the
biggest lie that people have convinced
themselves of
in our culture today
when we have so much access
to so much out there and i just walked
you through how to learn from it now if
you're not going to search on google
search on youtube join facebook groups
ask questions and you just and and look
on amazon for books
i can't help you
you have chosen to stay ignorant
you have chosen
to not walk the path to learn what you
need to
because it's easier for you to complain
whine and moan about how you're a victim
to everybody else in the world that
never set you up for success
or
you could literally do the five things
that i walked you through it took me 15
minutes to show you
on any topic you want to learn my
friends
any topic you want to learn here's the
other cool another part of the amazon
thing
if you liked a book you read through it
so let's say like i liked this book
again artificial intelligence i liked
this book a lot
scroll down
frequently bought together the ai is
showing us
other books that people bought on the
same topic
self-publishing comic books this is all
about publishing a comic book
there's no excuse my friends
there's no excuse
products related the structure of a
story
dragons and other mythical creatures
ray's anatomy
how to fail at stand-up comedy
hacking graphic novels how to write a
book
how to kill it in comedy
write an awesome paragraph step by step
we have a tool out there that we use as
well jasper
and i'll often use jasper
for an off label purpose
where i will actually go into the
template here
and say
what's the fastest way to learn
how to
write comic books
and i'll ask the ai
and it will literally generate me
a paragraph about this that i can learn
from
one of the most common questions every
writer has their own process it's
important to read as many as you can one
of the best things i learned study other
art forms like film and literature
and learn and learn about story
structure and pacing
what's the fastest way how to learn to
make
video games
it's complex join a community with a
mentor learn how to code coding
tutorials game design that's part of the
game journey okay
what's the fastest way to learn how to
sell more online courses
and so it's generating with ai
information that's that is
good information
on this
there's no one answer to this because
everyone learns differently
firstly
make sure that your courses are high
quality second market them effectively
by creating interesting descriptions
using social media offering discounts
don't be afraid if you feel
ask for help if you feel stuck literally
what i tell people all the time
engage with your audience build trust
you'll make more sales okay so now you
could go this
how do i
build more trust with an
audience
on social media
related to my
online course
about
thyroid care
or remove the tone
and the ai is actually going to generate
an answer to that question
and you can use this to create blog
posts and to create content
one way is to be authentic and
transparent share your personal story be
honest about your experiences
show that you're an expert with posts
and articles collaborate with social
media
establish yourself as a credible source
okay
how do i build more trust with an
audience about
songwriting and music publishing
this is one of my other clients
and so you're able to ask the ai these
questions google might not have the
answer for you but a tool like jasper
does
it's based off of the gt
gpt-3
project with open ai which is elon
musk's organization
that he started and the ai has scoured
the whole internet
and answers questions for you
faster than you could imagine
as a songwriter it's important to build
trust with your audience
share your process
be consistent
let your audience know that you're a
person not just a songwriter
share stories about your life and
experiences in the industry that's what
my client does that builds trust
for his program that helps people
okay
and so
my friends there's literally
there's no reason
for you
to struggle
there's no reason for you
to say
i don't know how to do
this stuff when there are resources that
are out there
youtube
facebook groups
amazon
google
jasper that you can literally type in
anything you want to learn and get
legitimate feedback
to learn more about those topics to
learn more about
anything that you want to know by
looking at what are the suggested videos
what are the suggested books what are
the results that go through here and and
and pull from a variety of results as
well
so some of you might say well i don't
have the time to do that
you have the time for what you
prioritize
the only reason you say you don't have
the time is because it's not important
enough to you
that's it we make time for what's
important for us
i want you could do this in less than 10
15 minutes a day you just take 15
minutes a day to do research like i just
showed you
and then the rest of the time you think
about what you researched and then come
back 15 minutes for 15 minutes later
the next day
some of you
might be like well i can't read through
a whole book because you have it stuck
in your brain that you have to complete
everything you start in one sitting
for it to be okay for you to do it my
friends
a bite at a time
a bite at a time you don't have to
complete
everything
start to finish
for you to be able to
to learn the things that you that you
want to learn
a bite at a time
what do you want to learn
i want to learn about this topic i want
to learn about that topic where are you
stuck what don't you know
and and here's the thing your brain
might shut down answering that question
because it's never been safe for you to
ask that question of yourself
this is where the deep work comes in
this is where possibly working with a
professional like a therapist or a
counselor or using a resource
like sevencups.com which is actually a
free resource it's not therapy
but it's it's a counselor and a listener
that you can talk to for free they also
do have licensed therapists on here
this is one of my favorite resources for
free
where you can find somebody to give you
counsel about certain things
trauma
why am i so afraid to ask for help
why am i so afraid to get the help that
i need
might be the scariest thing you've ever
done
but this app helped me
when i didn't have the budget
to pay for therapy
and then i started i paid for
betterhelp.com and i have a therapist
that i work through every week with this
the only reason you are not where you
want to be in your business is because
you have chosen to not do what it takes
that's it
you have chosen to not get the help you
have chosen to not
learn what you don't know
you can change that choice though
today starting today
and i hope that this episode has
unlocked
something in you
to teach you to show you
what's possible
there's no excuse to not learn anything
the cop-out
crappy reason
that i hear from people well you grew up
this way
and you were taught that way and people
like us we just
didn't grow up with that type of i'm
sorry my friends but my
mom learned how to do stuff this way
she homeschooled me she taught me this
learning methodology i've since taken it
and expanded it more and more
she's built multiple
eight-figure businesses
from having no knowledge on any of this
stuff
some of you might say well i'm just not
as smart as you jeremiah i'm just not as
whatever or you're saying you're way
smarter than me i'm sure a lot of you
are
my friends
that belief about your ability of not
being good enough
it's time to stop believing that it's
time to start believing that you can
have an unlimited level of intelligence
an unlimited level of knowledge
that you can learn anything that you
want to learn
and that you are not limited by your
experiences
if you so choose
you are not a victim to your biology
your upbringing
what side of the tracks you grew up on
unless you explicitly choose that those
are the excuses for why your life is
never going to change
and most people do they choose to never
change
because it's easier for them to live
inside of the box that they've always
been in
but not you if you're listening to this
right now i believe that you have what
it takes
now you have a choice to make
with great
knowledge and power comes great
responsibility you have a responsibility
now to take what i've just taught you in
this episode and to do something with it
what are you gonna do
we'll talk soon everybody have a good
one